{"tossups": [{"question": "At this event, Hellen Thorning Schmidt took a controversial selfie with David Cameron and Barack Obama, and Obama controversially shook hands with Raul Castro. Thamsanqa Jantjie suffered a schizophrenic episode while providing sign language translation at this event, which included a service in FNB Stadium, where Jacob Zuma was booed. For ten points, name this December 2013 event that memorialized the life of South Africa\u2019s first black president.", "answer": "Nelson<b> Mandela\u2019s funeral</b> (accept equivalents, like<b> Mandela\u2019s memorial service</b>)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "Z. Alexander Looby\u2019s house was bombed for his legal defense of participants in these events. James Lawson was expelled from Vanderbilt University for organizing these events, which led to the creation of SNCC [snick], the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee. The most famous of these demonstrations was conducted on February 1, 1960 by the Greensboro Four, and they began in Nashville, targeting drugstores like Walgreen\u2019s and Woolworth\u2019s. For ten points, name this form of peaceful protest that led to the desegregation of lunch counters.", "answer": "<b> sit in</b>s (prompt on general answers about civil rights protests before \u201cprotest\u201d is said)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Most of this man\u2019s work was done by assistants like Alex Gardner and Timothy Sullivan, this man was almost killed in the line of fire at Petersburg. One of this man\u2019s works shows Ambrose Burnside lamenting a defeat, whilst another depicts bodies strewn across the Bloody Lane. This man\u2019s works helped inspire one side of the penny coin, and this man\u2019s exhibition \u201cThe Dead of Antietam\u201d was praised for depicting the realities of war. For ten points, name this American photographer who took many photos of the Civil War.", "answer": "Mathew<b> Brady</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Frank Chimero suggested that one of this publication\u2019s regular features could consistently include a reference to LinkedIn. Kathryn Schulz\u2019s longread \u201cThe Really Big One\u201d about the impending Cascadia subduction event won a 2016 Pulitzer Prize for this magazine, as did the work of TV critic Emily Nussbaum. David Remnick is the current editor of this Cond\u00b4e Nast publication, which featured Saul Steinberg\u2019s \u201cView of the World from Ninth Avenue\u201d cover in 1976. The phrase \u201cOn the Internet, nobody knows you\u2019re a dog\u201d captioned a 1993 cartoon in, for ten points, what weekly magazine based in Manhattan?", "answer": "The<b> New Yorker</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "This city lost one battle after the Count d\u2019Arras led a charge of knights crying \u201cSaint George\u201d and a traitor chopped off the hand of its standard-bearer. One leader of this city, whose dominion was southeast of Modena and Lucca, wrote<em> The Triumph of the Cross</em> after Alexander VI excommunicated him for burning ancient texts and paintings in Bonfires of the Vanities. For ten points, name this city ruled by Savonarola, Lorenzo the Magnificent, and Cosimo de Medici.", "answer": "Republic of<b> Florence</b> (or<b> Firenze</b> or<b> Florentine Republic</b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Since 2000, a staggering 46 of these events have occurred during Liverpool\u2019s Grand National. In 2008, Eight Belles finished second to Big Brown, then suffered this fate due to cannon and sesamoid fractures. Two years earlier, a case of laminitis stemming from a leg injury suffered at Pimlico in Baltimore led to another of these events, though it occurred months after the Preakness Stakes. For ten points, name this athletic tragedy that befell Kentucky Derby winner Barbaro after shattering his right hind leg.", "answer": "<b> euthanization</b> (or other synonyms for<b> death</b>) of a race<b>horse</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "One leader of this country was filmed having his ears cut off while warlord Prince Johnson drank a Budweiser. During this country\u2019s first civil war, Joshua Milton Blahyi led an armed division of children known as the \u201cButt Naked brigade.\u201d That civil war ended with the 1997 election of Charles Taylor. Alongside Guinea and Sierra Leone, this country was at the centre of the West African Ebola outbreak. For ten points, name this African country, originally established as a country for free slaves, whose capital is Monrovia.", "answer": "<b> Liberia</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "Kepler predicted the 1631 occurrence of this event, but it was not visible from Europe. One of these in 1769 was studied from Tahiti during James Cook\u2019s first voyage to Australia. During these astronomical events, which occur in pairs eight years apart, spectroscopy can detect an atmosphere with much less sulfuric acid than commonly believed. For ten points, name these events in which a certain planet crosses between the Earth and Sun.", "answer": "<b> transit</b>s of<b> Venus</b> (accept<b> occultation of the Sun by Venus</b> or<b> eclipse of the Sun by Venus</b> or<b> solar eclipse by Venus</b>; prompt on partial answers, but do not accept or prompt on solar eclipse alone; accept descriptions of <b>Venus passing in front of the Sun</b> (as viewed from Earth) before FTP) <b>Second Quarter</b>", "metadata": "Science - Other Science - Astronomy"}, {"question": "This work includes a section based on a Lancashire dance later associated with sailors, and may have been commissioned as a way to \u201cshow up\u201d the Prince of Wales. The quieter orchestration of its G major portion indicates it was performed later at a \u201cchoice supper\u201d in Chelsea, and its first portion in F major included movements titled \u201cBour\u00b4ee\u201d and \u201cAlla Hornpipe\u201d. For ten points, name this set of three suites, commissioned in 1717 by George I for a floating barge concert along the Thames, which were composed by George Handel.", "answer": "<b> Water Music</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This leader appointed special officials called dharma mahamatras to propagate morality and relieve suffering. He attemped to convert Antiochus II Theos to his religion, as recounted in an inscription on a pillar. This monarch erected another pillar that features four lions standing on top of a drum, the Lion Capital of Sarnath, one of many inscribed with his rock edicts. For ten points, name this Mauryan emperor of India who, after conquering Kalinga, converted to Buddhism.", "answer": "<b> Ashoka</b> Maurya (or<b> Ashoka</b> the Great; or<b> Asoka</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "Barbara Ortiz Howard and Susan Ades Stone are leaders of an organization that supported this goal. A controversial projection for this goal suggested that a portrait by John Trumbull would be preserved on the obverse. A similar honor has more recently been bestowed on a co-publisher of<em> The Revolution</em>, as well as the Shoshone guide, Sacagawea. The success of this goal was officially announced in April 2016 by Jack Lew, the Treasury Secretary. For ten points, name this campaign that will replace Andrew Jackson with Harriet Tubman on a certain form of American legal tender.", "answer": "putting a<b> woman</b> on U.S.<b> paper currency</b> (accept any specific denomination, including $20 or $10 bills; prompt on partial answers, like \u201cputting a woman on U.S. money\u201d; do not accept or prompt any mention of coins)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This leader\u2019s decision to raise the price of meat and butter resulted in the Novocherkassk Massacre. A visit by this man to Roswell Garst\u2019s farm in Iowa convinced him of the utility of corn, which he attempted to introduce to his own nation and he attempted to increase agricultural production with the Virgin Lands campaign, starting in 1953, with a failed attempt to grow grain in Kazakhstan. For ten points, name this Soviet leader whose agricultural policies were not nearly as devastating as those of his predecessor, Joseph Stalin.", "answer": "Nikita<b> Khrushchev</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The legendary Arnold von Winkelried sacrificed himself to these weapons at the Battle of Sempach. Against these weapons, the Doppelsoldners and Rodeleros would break the deadlock created by their \u201cpush.\u201d These weapons, which were similar to the ancient (+) </b> <b>sarissa, repeatedly saved Ren\u00b4e II against Charles the Bold by using a tight \u201csquare\u201dformation. Arquebusiers surrounded users of these weapons in (*) </b> tercios, and the colorful Landsknechts and Swiss mercenaries heavily utilized them. For ten points, name these long Renaissance spears.", "answer": "<b> pike</b>s (prompt on spear before end)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "For ten points, name this 1964 event in which torpedo boats fired on the USS<em> Maddox</em> in an arm of the South China Sea, after which Congress authorized Lyndon Johnson\u2019s troop deployment to Vietnam.", "answer": "Gulf of<b> Tonkin</b> incident", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}